Manoj Chandhru R Email: manoj.chandhru@gmail.com

Contact no: +91 9986442034 Bangalore, Karnataka



Having 10.5 years of diversified experience in end-to-end application analysis and Production support/Enhancements of software applications. I would like to explore new opportunities in the area of Application Support/Maintenance, seeking a challenging position in an organization to make use of my expertise for enhancing productivity at the workplace, and ensuring high customer satisfaction.

Experience

Description: Deutsche Bank AG is a German global banking and financial services and has a large presence in Europe, the Americas, and Asia-Pacific. Managed an access operations team of Onsite and Off-shore; responsible for overseeing access management within Service Level Agreement (SLA's) and remediating vulnerabilities to adhere to enterprise policy in addition to adoption of regulatory compliance standards.

Jul 2012 - Apr 2014 Support Analyst

Tata Consultancy Services

- Provided ITIL based support of multiple legacy applications and administration for Corporate services and Finance integrity applications.
- Suggested the automation of a ticket generation process which ultimately saved more than \$1.25 MM of manual work effort annually for the client
- Assumed the role of Change Coordinator for my team, representing change orders for my team at weekly Change Advisory Board meetings.
- Created job aids, metrics and tracking spreadsheets, SOP to train and bring new team members on board and up to speed in a timely manner.

May 2014 - Nov 2016 Technical Lead-Application Maintenance & Deployment

Tata Consultancy Services

- Troubleshooting and resolving access management and provisioning workflow errors.
- Perform Identity and access management activities.
- Updating existing access management and provisioning workflows.
- Manage identity and access management support to business and technical teams in the design of standardized products and customized solutions.
- Onboarding the application.
- Assist in the development of performance metrics/measurements for the user access attestations
- Defect tracking, delivering Defect Report, Test execution Summary Report to the client and Create automated reports using report definition which will auto start the job automatically.
- Identifying the unexpected behavior of the service and interacting with the client and developer in order to resolve the issue.
- Involved in deployment activities using D1IM tools and application functional testing.

Dec 2016 - Mar 2022 Technical Project Lead- Identity and Access Management.

Tata Consultancy Services

- Perform IAM oversight process execution, to include reactionary steps when KPIs are not in a "green" status and escalation paths to leverage if required
- Assist with definition and rationalization of change management rigor for IAM changes
- Lead hands-on management and execution of the certification cycles pre-cycle, post-cycle, and during the cycle
- Serve as IAM lead as it relates to project engagement, IAM tool governance, analysis & implementation of automation opportunities, and security architecture/engineering consultation
- Strong understanding of Information Security concepts

- Independent thinking, willingness to "step outside the box" and take reasonable, calculated risks
- Experience in a fast paced, high stress environment
- Demonstrated ability to be reliable and flexible
- Demonstrated analytical, problem solving, and prioritization skills
- Review active privileges in the system and conclude on creation/modification of roles
- Communicate requirements to stakeholders, manage conflicts, issues and challenges in order to ensure that stakeholders and project team members remain in agreement on solution scope
- Plan and monitor to determine which activities are necessary to identify relevant stakeholders
- Analyze and document business requirements and interfacing with system/platform owners
- Currently working on Cloud migration project for the client.
- Overseeing Budgeting, Auditing and regulatory documents.

Mar 2022 – Present:

Tuebora Software Private Limited – Senior support Engineer.

Education

Jun 2007 - May 2011 : Kalasalingam University (Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and Communication Engineering)

Skills

RDBMS : MySQL, SQL server.

Tools : D1IM, Geneos, SQL Developer, MySQL Workbench, BMC Remedy, ServiceNow,

Dell1 Identity Manager, Optier, Google Cloud console, cloud Run, Kubernetes.

Windows Administration, IIS, SSIS, SSRS.

Languages : C#, C++, VB.Net
Web Technology : HTML, XML

Applications/IDE : Eclipse, Dream weaver
Testing : Manual Testing, JMeter

Process : Incident, Change, Problem & Escalation Management